[
    {
        "question": "<span> With a view to improve her health, she started exercising regularly.</span>",
        "option_1": "<span> With a view to improve her</span>",
        "option_2": "<span> health, she started </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> exercising regularly.</span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": "<span> The correct answer is: (a) With a view to improve her. “With the following verbs/ adjectives/ phrases ‘V1 + ing’ is used after ‘to’. Verb + used to, accustomed to, averse to, averse to, with a view to, addicted to, devoted to, in addition to, look forward to, object to, owing to, given to, taken to, prone to.”</span><p><span>The correct sentence should be: \" With a view to improving her health, she started exercising regularly.\"</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<a name=\"_Hlk165129628\"><span>Write poetry allows </span></a><span>her to express her emotions creatively. </span>",
        "option_1": "<span> Write poetry allows </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> her to express </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> her emotions creatively.</span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": "<span> the verb \"write\" should be used in its gerund form to function as a noun since it's part of the subject \"Writing poetry.\" Gerunds are verb forms that function as nouns, and they end in \"-ing.\" So, \"writing\" is the gerund form of \"write\" that correctly acts as a noun to describe the action or activity of composing poetry.</span><p><span>Therefore, the correct sentence is: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">“Writing poetry allows her to express her emotions creatively.” </span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> The situation proved </span><a name=\"_Hlk165283271\"><span>challengingly for even</span></a><span> the most experienced climbers. </span>",
        "option_1": "<span> The situation proved </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> challengingly for even</span>",
        "option_3": "<span> the most experienced climbers.</span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "2",
        "solution": "<p><span>The correct option is: (b) challengingly for even</span></p><p><span>In this sentence, \"challengingly\" is an adverb, but according to the rule (“'be', 'become', 'turn', 'get', 'grow', 'keep', 'make', and 'prove' are qualified by an adjective and not by an adverb\"). Therefore, \"challengingly\" should be replaced with an adjective like \"challenging\" to make the sentence grammatically correct. </span></p><p><span>So, the corrected sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"The situation proved challenging for even the most experienced climbers.\"</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> She qualified herself for the final round of the competition. </span>",
        "option_1": "<span> She qualified herself for </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> the final round </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> of the competition.</span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error</span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": "<span> The correct option is: (a) She qualified herself for</span><p><a name=\"_Hlk165289304\"><span>According to the rule “keep, stop, turn, qualify, bathe, move, rest, hide\" these verbs do not take reflexive pronouns.” </span></a></p><p><span>In this sentence, \"qualified\" should not be followed by the reflexive pronoun \"herself\" when referring to qualifying for something like the final round of a competition. Therefore, \"herself\" should be removed to make the sentence grammatically correct.</span></p><p><span>The corrected sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"She qualified for the final round of the competition.\"</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> They relied to him for guidance.</span>",
        "option_1": "<span> They relied </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> to him </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> for guidance. </span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "2",
        "solution": "<span> The correct option is: (b) to him</span><p><span>In this sentence, the verb \"relied\" should be followed by the preposition \"on,\" not \"to,\" when expressing dependence on someone for guidance. Therefore, \"to\" should be replaced with \"on\" to make the sentence grammatically correct.</span></p><p><span>The corrected sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"They</span><span> relied</span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\"> on him for guidance.\"</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> We must get this letter send as soon as possible. </span>",
        "option_1": "<span> We must get this letter</span>",
        "option_2": "<span> send</span>",
        "option_3": "<span> as soon as possible</span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error</span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "2",
        "solution": "<span> The correct option is: (b) send</span><p><span>Change ‘send’ to ‘sent’. ‘V3’ comes after ‘get’.</span></p><p><span>So the corrected sentence is: We must get this letter sent as soon as possible.</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> They availed themselves and benefited from the resources provided.</span>",
        "option_1": "<span> They availed themselves and </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> benefited from </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> the resources provided.</span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": "<span>The correct option is: (a) They availed themselves and</span><p><span>In the sentence \"They availed themselves and benefited from the resources provided,\" each verb should be followed by its respective preposition to maintain a</span><span>parallel structure and adhere to the rule provided. Therefore, \"availed themselves\" should be followed by \"of\" to ensure consistency with the preposition \"from\" used after \"benefited.\"</span></p><p><span>The corrected sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"They availed themselves of and benefited from the resources provided.”</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> The committee elected her as president unanimously.</span>",
        "option_1": "<span> The committee </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> elected her as</span>",
        "option_3": "<span> president unanimously.</span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "2",
        "solution": "<span> In this sentence, the adverb \"as\" is used after the verb \"elected.\" According to the rule adverb 'as' is not used with the following verbs: name, elect, think, consider, call, appoint, make, choose\".</span><p><span>Therefore, the correct answer is: “</span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">The committee elected her president unanimously.”</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> As she has practiced diligently, she is confident to perform exceptionally well in the competition.</span>",
        "option_1": "<span> As she has practiced diligently, </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> she is confident to perform </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> exceptionally well in the competition. </span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "2",
        "solution": "<p><span>The correct option is: (b) she is confident to perform.</span></p><p><span>Confident of performing is correct because ‘of’ is used with ‘confident’, </span><a name=\"_Hlk165305836\"><span>and V1 + ing (gerund) is used after all prepositions.</span></a></p><p><span>Therefore, the correct sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">“As she has practiced diligently, she is confident of performing exceptionally well in the competition.”</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> Being allergy season, she always carries tissues with her.</span>",
        "option_1": "<span> Being allergy season, </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> she always carries </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> tissues with her. </span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": "<span> The correct answer is: “(a) Being allergy season.</span><p><span>If ‘It’ is not used before ‘being’, ‘I’ becomes the subject of ‘allergy season’ and this gives a wrong meaning to the sentence. Thus ‘It being allergy season’ must be used.</span></p><p><span>Therefore, the correct sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">“It Being allergy season, she always carries tissues with her.” </span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> The children played with a break toy found in the attic.</span>",
        "option_1": "<span> The children played </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> with a break toy </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> found in the attic.</span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "2",
        "solution": "<span> In the given sentence, the word \"break\" is used as a noun, but it should be used as an adjective to describe the toy. Adjectives modify or describe nouns, while nouns typically name a person, place, thing, or idea. In this context, \"broken\" should be used instead of \"break\" to describe the toy. </span><p><span>Here's the corrected sentence: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"The children played with a broken toy found in the attic.\" </span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> He made surely the presentation was flawless.</span>",
        "option_1": "<span> He made surely </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> the presentation </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> was flawless. </span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": "<p><span>The correct option is: (a) He made surely</span></p><p><span>In this sentence, \"surely\" is an adverb, but according to the rule (“'be', 'become', 'turn', 'get', 'grow', 'keep', 'make', and 'prove' are qualified by an adjective and not by an adverb\"). Therefore, \"surely\" should be replaced with an adjective like \"sure\" to make the sentence grammatically correct. </span></p><p><span>So, the corrected sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"He made sure the presentation was flawless.\"</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<a name=\"_Hlk165284722\"><span>The comedian amused </span></a><span>herself by watching old comedy sketches. </span>",
        "option_1": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> The comedian amused </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> herself by watching </span>",
        "option_4": "<span> old comedy sketches.</span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": "<span> The sentence is correct as it is. There is no error.</span><p><span>According to the rule, the</span><span>following verbs will also take a reflexive pronoun after them: (acquit, absent, avail, reconcile, amuse, resign, avenge, enjoy, exert, apply, adapt, adjust, pride), It should take a reflexive pronoun after it. </span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<p>She exerted to <a name=\"_Hlk165286412\">finish the project </a>before the deadline.</p>",
        "option_1": "<p>She exerted to</p>",
        "option_2": "<p>finish the project</p>",
        "option_3": "<p>before the deadline.</p>",
        "option_4": "<p>No error</p>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": "<p>The correct option is: (a) She exerted to</p> <p>In this sentence, the verb \"exerted\" should be followed by a preposition like \"herself\" to indicate that she made an effort. Therefore, the corrected sentence would be: \"She exerted herself to finish the project before the deadline.\"</p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> After a long day of hiking, they rested themselves under a tree. </span>",
        "option_1": "<span> After a long day of </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> hiking, they rested </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> themselves under a tree.</span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error</span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "3",
        "solution": "<span>The correct option is: (c) themselves under a tree.</span><p><span>According to the</span><span>rules “keep, stop, turn, qualify, bathe, move, rest, hide\" these verbs that do not take reflexive pronouns.” </span></p><p><span>In this sentence, \"rested\" should not be followed by the reflexive pronoun \"themselves\" when referring to taking a rest. Therefore, \"themselves\" should be removed to make the sentence grammatically correct.</span></p><p><span>The corrected sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"After a long day of hiking, they rested under a tree.\"</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> She bought ingredients to bake. </span>",
        "option_1": "<span> She bought </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> ingredients </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> to bake. </span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "3",
        "solution": "<span> According to the rule that an infinitive qualifying a noun should take a suitable preposition, </span><p><span>The corrected sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"She bought ingredients to bake with.\" </span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> He describes his painting a reflection of his emotions.</span>",
        "option_1": "<span> He describes his</span>",
        "option_2": "<span> painting a reflection </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> of his emotions. </span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "2",
        "solution": "<p><span>The correct option is: (b) painting a reflection</span></p><p><span>In the sentence \"He describes his painting a reflection of his emotions,\" the adverb \"as\" is missing after the verb \"describes.\" According to the rule </span><span style=\"font-family:'Segoe UI';color:#0d0d0d;background-color:#ffffff\">adverb 'as' can be used with following verbs: regard, describe, define, treat, view, know.\"</span><span>, the adverb \"as\" should be used with the verb \"describes\" when connecting the subject with what is being described. </span></p><p><span>Therefore, the sentence should be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"He describes his painting as a reflection of his emotions.\"</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> We are interested in learn new languages. </span>",
        "option_1": "<span> We are </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> interested in learn </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> new languages. </span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "2",
        "solution": "<span> The correct option is: (b) interested in learn</span><p><span>In the sentence \"We are interested in learn new languages,\" the verb \"learn\" should be in the gerund form (-ing form) to follow the preposition \"in\" correctly. </span></p><p><span>Therefore, the corrected sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"We are interested in learning new languages.\"</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> She is devoted to help those in need in her community.</span>",
        "option_1": "<span> She is devoted to help </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> those in need </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> in her community. </span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": "<span> The correct sentence is: (a) She is devoted to help. With the following verbs/ adjectives/ phrases ‘V1 + ing’ is used after ‘to’. Verb + used to, accustomed to, averse to, averse to, with a view to, addicted to, devoted to, in addition to, look forward to, object to, owing to, given to, taken to, prone to. </span><p><span>The correct sentence should be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"She is devoted to helping those in need in her community.\"</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<p>She used to smoking, but she quit a year ago.</p>",
        "option_1": "<p>She used to</p>",
        "option_2": "<p>smoking, but she</p>",
        "option_3": "<p>quit a year ago.</p>",
        "option_4": "<p>No error</p>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "2",
        "solution": "<p>The correct answer is: (b) smoking, but she. The error is in part (b). The correct form should be \"She used to smoke,\" instead of \"She used to smoking.\" \"Used to\" is followed by the base form of the verb (smoke), not the -ing form (smoking).</p> <p>Therefore, the correct sentence would be: “She used to smoke, but she quit a year ago.”</p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> Being afraid of heights, she refused to go on the roller coaster. </span>",
        "option_1": "<span> Being afraid of heights, </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> she refused to go </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> on the roller coaster.</span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "4",
        "solution": "<span> The correct answer is: (d) No error. \"Being afraid of heights,\" is a participial phrase that provides additional information about the subject \"she.\" It explains the reason or condition (being afraid of heights) that influenced her action. \"she refused to go\" is the main clause of the sentence. It contains the subject \"she\" and the verb \"refused,\" indicating her action of declining to go on the roller coaster. </span>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> They played soccer skilfull in the tournament.</span>",
        "option_1": "<span> They played </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> soccer skilfull </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> in the tournament.</span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "2",
        "solution": "<span> The error is in option (b). \"Skilful\" should be replaced with \"skilfully\" to form the adverb of manner correctly.</span><p><span>The correct sentence should be: “</span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">They played soccer skilfully in the tournament.”</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> The aroma of freshly baked bread smells heavenly in the kitchen. </span>",
        "option_1": "<span> The aroma of freshly </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> baked bread smells </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> heavenly in the kitchen.</span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "4",
        "solution": "<span> The correct answer is: No error</span><p><span>\"Heavenly\" can function as both an adjective and an adverb. In the sentence \"The aroma of freshly baked bread smells heavenly in the kitchen,\" \"heavenly\" is used as an adjective to describe the quality of the smell. It describes how the smell is perceived, indicating that it is very pleasant or divine. </span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> He availed of the opportunity to learn new skills. </span>",
        "option_1": "<span> He availed of </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> the opportunity to </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> learn new skills. </span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": "<span> The correct option is: (a) He availed of</span><p><span>In this sentence, \"availed\" is used as a verb, and according to the rule following verbs will also take reflexive pronoun after them: (acquit, absent, avail, reconcile, amuse, resign, avenge, enjoy, exert, apply, adapt, adjust, pride). It should take a reflexive pronoun after it. Therefore, \"availed\" should be followed by a reflexive pronoun like \"himself.\" </span></p><p><span>The corrected sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"He availed himself of the opportunity to learn new skills.\" </span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> They adjusted to the new schedule without complaint. </span>",
        "option_1": "<span> They adjusted to </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> the new schedule </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> without complaint. </span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": "<span> The correct option is: They adjusted to </span><p><span>In this sentence, the verb \"adjusted\" should be followed by a reflexive pronoun but According to the rule-following verbs will also take reflexive pronouns after them: (acquit, absent, avail, reconcile, amuse, resign, avenge, enjoy, exert, apply, adapt, adjust, pride), It should take a reflexive pronoun after it. Therefore, \"adjusted\" should be followed by a reflexive pronoun like \"themselves.\" </span></p><p><span>The corrected sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"They adjusted themselves to the new schedule without complaint.\"</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<p>They cared of their elderly parents.</p>",
        "option_1": "<p>They cared</p>",
        "option_2": "<p>of their</p>",
        "option_3": "<p>elderly parents.</p>",
        "option_4": "<p>No error</p>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "2",
        "solution": "<p>The correct option is: (b) of their</p> <p>In this sentence, the verb \"cared\" should be followed by the preposition \"for,\" not \"of,\" when expressing concern or responsibility for someone. Therefore, \"of\" should be replaced with \"for\" to make the sentence grammatically correct.</p> <p>The corrected sentence would be: \"They cared for their elderly parents.\"</p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> If I was you, I would apologize for the misunderstanding. </span>",
        "option_1": "<span> If I was you, </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> I would apologize </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> for the misunderstanding. </span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error</span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": ""
    },
    {
        "question": "<p>Learn a new language is on her bucket list.</p>",
        "option_1": "<p>Learn a new</p>",
        "option_2": "<p>language is on</p>",
        "option_3": "<p>her bucket list.</p>",
        "option_4": "<p>No error</p>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": "<p>The correct replacement for \"Learn\" is \"to learn.\" When a verb is used as a noun, it's often expressed in its infinitive form (\"to + base form of the verb\"). In this case, \"to learn\" functions as a noun phrase indicating an activity, so the corrected sentence should be: \"To learn a new language is on her bucket list.\"</p> <p>Therefore, the correct answer is: “To learn a new language is on her bucket list.”</p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> May the flowers blooms </span><a name=\"_Hlk165298576\"><span>in the garden. </span></a>",
        "option_1": "<span> May the </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> flowers blooms </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> in the garden.</span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "2",
        "solution": "<p><span>The correct option is: (b) flowers blooms</span></p><p><span>In optative sentences, plural verbs are used with singular subjects. Therefore, \"blooms\" should be changed to \"bloom\" to match the plural verb form required in this construction.</span></p><p><span>The corrected sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"May the flowers bloom in the garden.\"</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<a name=\"_Hlk165288583\"><span>Hemant stopped himself </span></a><span>the argument before </span><a name=\"_Hlk165288600\"><span>it escalated further.</span></a>",
        "option_1": "<span> Hemant stopped himself </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> the argument before </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> it escalated further. </span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": "<span> The correct option is: (a) Hemant stopped himself</span><p><span>According to the</span><span>rule “keep, stop, turn, qualify, bathe, move, rest, hide\" these verbs do not take reflexive pronouns.”</span></p><p><span>In this sentence, \"stopped\" should not be followed by the reflexive pronoun \"himself\" when referring to stopping an action or event like an argument. Therefore, \"himself\" should be removed to make the sentence grammatically correct.</span></p><p><span>The corrected sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"Hemant stopped the argument before it escalated further.\"</span></p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<p>Himanshu should pride <a name=\"_Hlk165285727\">on being able to </a>work smoothly under pressure too.</p>",
        "option_1": "<p>Himanshu should pride</p>",
        "option_2": "<p>on being able to work</p>",
        "option_3": "<p>smoothly under pressure too.</p>",
        "option_4": "<p>No error</p>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "1",
        "solution": "<p>The correct option is: Himanshu should pride</p> <p>In this sentence, the verb \"pride\" should be followed by a reflexive pronoun but According to the rule following verbs will also take reflexive pronoun after them: (acquit, absent, avail, reconcile, amuse, resign, avenge, enjoy, exert, apply, adapt, adjust, pride), It should take a reflexive pronoun after it. Therefore, \"pride\" should be followed by a reflexive pronoun like \"himself.\"</p> <p>Therefore, the corrected sentence would be: \"Himanshu should pride himself on being able to work smoothly under pressure too.\"</p>"
    },
    {
        "question": "<span> He apologized of her for his behavior.</span>",
        "option_1": "<span> He apologized </span>",
        "option_2": "<span> of her for </span>",
        "option_3": "<span> his behaviour.</span>",
        "option_4": "<span> No error </span>",
        "option_5": "",
        "answer": "2",
        "solution": "<span> The correct option is: (b) of her for</span><p><span>In this sentence, the verb \"apologized\" should be followed by the preposition \"to,\" not \"of,\" when expressing an apology to someone. Therefore, \"of\" should be replaced with \"to\" to make the sentence grammatically correct.</span></p><p><span>The corrected sentence would be: </span><span style=\"text-decoration:underline\">\"He apologized to her for his behavior.\"</span></p>"
    }
]